Preliminary Guide to the University Architect Records, 1967 - 2000, 2008 UA.10.07.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
University Architect records
1971 - 2000, 2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Architect
UA.10.07.0001
16 Linear Feet
The University Architect, as well as the individuals in the Office of the University Architect, serve to meet the master planning, project management, design services, capital budgeting, real estate, and space planning needs of Duke University. Records include financial reports, project files, proposals, inspection reports, photographs, technical drawings, correspondence, minutes, agendas, and campus master plans related to construction and renovation projects, land use, space management, and planning at Duke University. English.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The University Architect Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1995-2002, 2008
Historical Note
The University Architect, as well as the individuals in the Office of the University Architect, serve to meet the master planning, project management, design services, capital budgeting, real estate, and space planning needs of Duke University.
Collection Overview
Collection includes financial reports, project files, proposals, inspection reports, photographs, technical drawings, correspondence, minutes, agendas, and campus master plans related to construction and renovation projects, land use, space management, and planning at Duke University.
Related Material
Educational Facilities Committee Records.
Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
College buildings -- Designs and plans; College buildings -- North Carolina; Athletic fields -- North Carolina -- Management; College buildings -- Planning; Duke University. University Architect; Duke University -- Planning; Duke University -- Buildings
- Duke University Construction Program Financial Report, 1971-2000
  Scope and Contents note
  Summary data on construction projects, including budgets, approvals, schedules, and related information.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Records dated 1997 and later are closed for 25 years from the date of origin except by permission in writing from the Office of the University Architect.
  - Financial Report, 1971-1974 (Box 8)
    Scope and Contents
    Call number: 378. 756 D877DW
  - Blue Book, 1998 (Box 8)
  - Blue Book, 1999 (Box 8)
  - Blue Book, 2000 (Box 8)
- Addition, 1995 [Accession A1995-9]
  Chiefly project files that date from the 1960s to the 1980s (bulk 1973-1981). The files primarily pertain to new construction and renovations on East, West, and Central campuses, as well as the Medical Center. They include project sheets, invoices, financial statements, proposals, inspection reports, and memoranda. Projects represented include the Medical Center Parking Garage II, renovations at Wallace Wade Stadium, renovations on East Campus, construction of the Seeley G. Mudd Library, the extension of the steam line, renovations and asbestos removal in the School of Law, and the building of the Central Campus Apartments.
  Partial folder list:
  - Highland Hospital; asbestos removal (Box 1)
  - Woman's College Center (Box 1)
  - Medical Center Parking Garage II (Box 1)
  - Music Building (Box 1)
  - Cancer Research Facility III (Box 1)
  - Medical Center Library; Construction progress photographs (Box 2)
  - Steamline extension: East and West campuses (Box 2)
  - Old Chemistry renovations: Graduate School of Business Administration (Box 2)
  - Track revitalization (Box 2)
  - Hart House (Box 2)
  - Rare Book Room air conditioning (Box 2)
  - Woodwork in West Campus dining hall (Box 2)
  - Psychical Research Center (Box 3)
  - Psychological Services Center (Box 3)
  - Park on Cornwallis Road (Box 3)
  - Chapel organs: Flentrop and Aeolian (Box 3)
  - Daycare center (Box 3)
  - Duke Hospital North (Box 3)
  - Duke Hospital North, Affirmative Action (Box 3)
  - Flow Facility Lab (Box 3)
  - Law School: asbestos removal (Box 3)
  - WDBS (Box 4)
  - Service Center (Box 4)
  - Central Campus Apartments (Box 4)
  - Perkins Library windows (Box 5)
  - Law School renovations (Box 5)
  - Wallace Wade stadium renovations (Box 5)
- Addition, 1999 [Accession A1999-26]
  Includes minutes, correspondence, reports, technical drawings. Also included are minutes and agendas of the Buildings and Grounds Committee of the Board of Trustees (1965-1986) and the Educational Facilities Committee (1978-1986). Subject files include the 1986 Urban Land Institute study and land use, roads and traffic, the 1984 Flowers Drive failure, Law School planning (1984-1988), Art Museum planning (1987-1990), and athletic facilities (1984-1987).
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1965-1986 (Box 6)
  - Subject files (Box 7)
- Addition, 2000 [Accession A2000-12]
  Lease forms, correspondence, and related records concerning the campus post offices. These have been known as the College Station, or the Duke Station, and has been located in the Crowell Building on East Campus, in the West Campus Union, and in the Bryan Center.
  - Campus Post Offices records (Box 8)
- Addition, 2000 [Accession A2000-23]
  Duke University Campus Master Plan was prepared for a presentation to the Buildings and Grounds Committee of the Board of Trustees, held May 12, 2000.
  - Campus Master Plan, Final Draft, May 2000 (Box 9)
  - Campus Master Plan, Draft, November 1999 (Box 9)
  - Action Plan 2000, Draft, November 1999 (Box 9)
  - Draft, 1987 (Box 9)
- Addition, 2008 [Accession UA2008-40]
  - Duke University Landscape Design Guidelines, 2008 (Box 9)